<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>kubectl on Yoichi Kawasaki</title>
    <link>https://unofficialism.info/tags/kubectl/</link>
    <description>Recent content in kubectl on Yoichi Kawasaki</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://unofficialism.info/profile.jpg</url>
      <link>https://unofficialism.info/profile.jpg</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://unofficialism.info/tags/kubectl/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>kubectl plugin - SOCKS5 proxy to Services or Pods in the cluster</title>
      <link>https://unofficialism.info/posts/kubectl-plugin-socks5-proxy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unofficialism.info/posts/kubectl-plugin-socks5-proxy/</guid>
      <description>I’ve published a new kubectl plugin called kubectl-plugin-socks5-proxy. This is a kubectl plugin that creates a local SOCKS5 proxy through which you can access to Services or Pods in a Kubernetes cluster.
What the plugin actually does is that it create a SOCKS proxy server Pod in a Kubernetes cluster and forwards a local port (default:1080) to the proxy. So you can access to Servcies or Pods in Kuberenetes cluster by using the local port as SOCKS5 proxy like this:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GitHub Actions - Kubernetes tools installer</title>
      <link>https://unofficialism.info/posts/action-setup-kube-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unofficialism.info/posts/action-setup-kube-tools/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve published a new GitHub Action called action-setup-kube-tools (View on Marketplace). The action installs Kubernetes tools (kubectl, kustomize, helm, kubeval, conftest, and yq) and cache them on the runner. This is a typescript version of stefanprodan/kube-tools with no command input param.
Usage Inputs Parameter Required Default Value Description kubectl false 1.18.2 kubectl version. kubectl vesion can be found here kustomize false 3.5.5 kustomize version. kustomize vesion can be found here helm false 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Kubernetes Metrics using kubectl</title>
      <link>https://unofficialism.info/posts/getting-kubernetes-metrics-using-kubectl/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unofficialism.info/posts/getting-kubernetes-metrics-using-kubectl/</guid>
      <description>There are various ways to obtain Kubernetes metrics which you can use to visualize, monitor and alert on your metrics. In reality you most likely use managed or unmanaged OSS metrics collection and visualization tools, but in this post, I introduce how to get raw Kubernetes metrics using kubectl.
Kubernetes Raw Metrics via Prometheus metrics endpoint Many Kubernetes components exposes their metrics via the /metrics endpoint, including API server, etcd and many other add-ons.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
