<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>GitHubActions on Yoichi Kawasaki</title>
    <link>https://unofficialism.info/tags/githubactions/</link>
    <description>Recent content in GitHubActions on Yoichi Kawasaki</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://unofficialism.info/profile.jpg</url>
      <link>https://unofficialism.info/profile.jpg</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://unofficialism.info/tags/githubactions/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>GitHub Actions - Kubernetes tools installer</title>
      <link>https://unofficialism.info/posts/action-setup-kube-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unofficialism.info/posts/action-setup-kube-tools/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve published a new GitHub Action called action-setup-kube-tools (View on Marketplace). The action installs Kubernetes tools (kubectl, kustomize, helm, kubeval, conftest, and yq) and cache them on the runner. This is a typescript version of stefanprodan/kube-tools with no command input param.
Usage Inputs    Parameter Required Default Value Description     kubectl false 1.18.2 kubectl version. kubectl vesion can be found here   kustomize false 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GitHub Actions - Elastic Cloud Control (ecctl) tool installer</title>
      <link>https://unofficialism.info/posts/action-setup-ecctl/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unofficialism.info/posts/action-setup-ecctl/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve published a new GitHub Action called action-setup-ecctl (View on Marketplace). The action installs a specific version of ecctl (Elastic Cloud control tool) and cache it on the runner.
Usage Inputs    Parameter Required Default Value Description     version false latest Ecctl tool version such as v1.0.0-beta3. Ecctl vesion can be found here.     Supported Environments: Linux and macOS
 Outputs    Parameter Description     ecctl-path ecctl command path    Sample Workflow A specific version of ecctl can be setup by giving an input - version like this: {% raw %}</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GitHub Actions - SQLCheck Action</title>
      <link>https://unofficialism.info/posts/action-sqlcheck/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unofficialism.info/posts/action-sqlcheck/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve published a new GitHub Action called SQLCheck Action (View on Marketplace). The action automatically identifies anti-patterns in SQL queries using sqlcheck when PR is requested and comment on the PR if risks are found in the queries.
Usage Supports pull_request event type.
Inputs    Parameter Required Default Value Description     post-comment false true Post comment to PR if it&amp;rsquo;s true   token true &amp;quot;&amp;quot; GitHub Token in order to add comment to PR   risk-level false 3 Set of SQL anti-patterns to check: 1,2, or 3- 1 (all anti-patterns, default)- 2 (only medium and high risk anti-patterns)- 3 (only high risk anti-patterns)   verbose false false Add verbose warnings to SQLCheck analysis result   postfixes false &amp;ldquo;sql&amp;rdquo; List of file postfix to match ( separator: comma )    Sample Workflow  .</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
